# YUYUN FRANCIS BERINYUY

# Douala, Cameroon +237 673 993 113| francisberi@yahoo.com

LinkedIn: yuyunfrancis

A highly skilled and motivated Software Engineer and a Ui/Ux Designer with some experience in web design and development knowledge. I am driven to create impacts with the use of technology by providing sustainable solutions to real-world problems. I am dynamic, proactive, hardworking, disciplined, and focused. With these qualities, I am able to withstand any pressure to succeed

#### **EDUCATION**

• ICT University Yaounde, Cameroon BSc with Honors in Software Engineering CGPA 3.44/4.00 09/2021

• LMBC Bonamoussadi, Douala, CMR Advance Level Certificate

08/2018

## SKILLS AND CORE COMPETENCES

- Mobile App Development (Flutter)
- Frontend Web Developer
- Intermediate Graphic Designer
- UI/UX Designer (Adobe XD / Figma)
- Project Management
- Database Management (MYSQL)
- Good Knowledge of CMS

- Organizational and planning skills Teamwork
- Strong communication skills
- Data collection and management Attention to detail
- Problem-Solving

## RESEARCH WORK

• Design and Implementation of a Taxi Booking System with Geolocalization Functionality (A Case Study of Cameroon). A research project in partial fulfillment of the Bachelor's Degree.

## LEADERSHIP AND VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

- ICT University Department Representative where I: Organized tech competitions for young talents; organized a night of code sessions, where we worked on real-life projects all night; organized talks and conferences on tech for the student body.
- Chief Technical Officer and Co-Founder at Energetic Youths in Action (EYIA), an NGO aimed at helping the poor and empowering youths in all spheres of thier lives.

## **CONFERENCES ATTENDED**

• Took part in the SDG Innovation Challenge organized by Melton Foundation 11/2021

• Took part in the NervTek Community Challenge where we presented a project on Garbage bin tracker in 2021

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

•	Frontend Developer	02/2022-Present
	AgroSmart Inc	
•	Software Developer Intern	11/2021-01/2022
	Is Dev Experts	
•	Intern at HANDY Services	10/2021-11/2021
	Redesigned pages of their website	
•	Intern at ARRAH SOLUTIONS	06/2021- 08/2021
	Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through	
	deployment.	
•	Intern at KEN TECHNOLOGIES	04/2021-06/2021
	Prepared documents for data entry	
	Verified, updated, and corrected source documents.	
•	Computer Science Teacher Zudom College Nyom	09/2020-06/2021

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

African Market Place Positioning
 Offered by CELBMD AFRICA
Basics of Project Management course
 Offered by the International Business Management Institute Berlin, Germany

Language: English – Advanced

French – Intermediate

### References:

• Name: Engineer Ubah Johnson

Email: ubah.johnson@ictuniversity.edu.cm

• Name: Dr. Javnyuy Joybert

Email: <u>Javnyuy@cosdefgroup.co</u>